Guide to the David Leavitt Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
David Leavitt papers
1935-2015
YCAL MSS 724
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
56.72
(74 boxes) + 1 roll
This collection consists of correspondence, writings, personal papers, scrapbooks, printed material, artwork, computer disks, audio tapes, and videotapes documenting the life and writing career of David Leavitt, spanning from 1935 to 2015.
Leavitt, David, 1961-
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 18, 45, 58 (computer disks): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 42, 59, and 74 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 73 (electronic media): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 46: Restricted Fragile Material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
June 1998 Acquisitions: purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Ezra Pound Archive Fund and Adele Gutman Nathan Theatrical Collection Fund, 1998.
March 2002 Acquisition: purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 2002.
May 2006 Acquisition: purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Donald Windham-Sandy Campbell Collection Endowment Fund, 2006.
December 2014 Acquisition: purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 2014.
May 2016 Acquisition: purchased from David Leavitt on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2016.
Arrangement
Organized into five groupings: June 1998 Acquisitions; March 2002 Acquisition; May 2006 Acquisition; December 2014 Acquisition; and May 2016 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time.
Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with and/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, writings can be found in all three groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Researchers should also note that similar material can be arranged differently in each acquisition, depending on how the material was organized when it was received by the library.
David Leavitt
David Leavitt is an American writer who was born in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania on June 23, 1961, and graduated from Yale in 1983. Leavitt is known as a leader in the American gay literature movement, and has been nominated for and awarded prizes including the Willets Prize for fiction (1982) and the O. Henry Award (1984).
His major works include Family Dancing (1984), The Lost Language of Cranes (1986), Equal Affections (1989), A Place I've Never Been (1990), While England Sleeps (1993), Arkansas (1997), The Page Turner (1998), Martin Bauman: Or, A Sure Thing (2000), The Marble Quilt (2001), Florence, a Delicate Case (2002), The Body of Jonah Boyd (2004), The Man Who Knew Too Much: Alan Turing and the Invention of the Computer (2005), and The Indian Clerk (2007). He also co-authored or edited a number of books with Mark Mitchell, including Penguin Book of Gay Short Stories (1994), Italian Pleasures (1996), Pages Passed from Hand to Hand: The Hidden Tradition of Homosexual Literature in English from 1748 to 1914 (1997), E.M. Forster, Selected Stories (2001), In Maremma: Life and a House in Southern Tuscany (2001). He has also contributed to periodicals including Esquire, Harper's, New Yorker, New York Times Book Review, New York Times Magazine, and Village Voice.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of correspondence, writings, personal papers, scrapbooks, printed material, artwork, computer disks, audio tapes, and video tapes documenting the life and writing career of David Leavitt, spanning from 1935 to 2015.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Gay authors; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Leavitt, David, 1961-
- June 1998 Acquisitions, 1960-1998; 1; 15.68; (20 boxes)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Ezra Pound Archive Fund and Adele Gutman Nathan Theatrical Collection Fund, 1998.
  Arrangement
  Arranged under seven headings: Correspondence, Correspondence from Publishers, Writings, Articles on Leavitt, Reviews, Personal Papers, and Audiovisual Material and Computer Disks.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 74 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 18 (computer disks): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains correspondence, writings, personal papers, printed material, scrapbooks, audio tapes, video tapes, computer disks and other papers related to David Leavitt. Includes manuscripts and other papers relating to his works While England Sleeps, Family Dancing and The Lost Language of Cranes.
  - Correspondence
    - Postcards, [undated] (Box 1)
    - Postcards, 1981-1998; 11 (Box 1)
    - Cards, [undated] (Box 1)
    - Cards, 1980-1997; 3 (Box 1)
    - Letters, [undated] (Box 1)
    - Letters, 1970-1998; 13 (Box 1)
    - Letters from Leavitt, 1993-1997; 3 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence from Publishers
    - Little Brown, 1994-1997 (Box 1)
    - Houghton Mifflin, 1997 (Box 1)
    - The Viking Press, 1983-1993; 2 (Box 1)
    - Chatto and Windus, 1997 16 December (Box 1)
    - Wylie Agency, 1982-1998 (Box 1)
    - Esquire Fax, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Catalogs, 1984-1998 (Box 1)
  - Writings
    - Another Land, [undated] (Box 2)
    - Arkansas, 1997; 4 (Box 2)
    - Arkansas: reviews, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Auntie Maim, [undated] (Box 2)
    - Cartoons, [undated] (Box 2)
    - Citizens of the World, [undated]; 4 (Box 2)
    - The Crime of the Survivor, [undated] (Box 2)
    - Concerts for the Left Hand, [undated] (Box 2)
    - The Dungeon, [undated] (Box 2)
    - Errands, [undated] (Box 2)
    - The Extra Ordinary, [undated] (Box 2)
    - Family Dancing: unsorted, 1984-1987; 9 (Box 2)
    - Family Dancing: unsorted, 1984-1987; 4 (Box 3)
    - Aliens, [undated] (Box 3)
    - Counting Months, [undated]; 2 (Box 3)
    - Danny in Transit, [undated]; 2 (Box 3)
    - Dedicated, [undated]; 2 (Box 3)
    - The Lost Cottage, [undated]; 2 (Box 3)
    - Outhere, 1983; 2 (Box 3)
    - In the Radiation Therapy Center, 1983; 2 (Box 3)
    - Territory, [undated]; 3 (Box 3)
    - Family Dancing Reviews, circa 1985 (Box 3)
    - Fear, [undated] (Box 3)
    - Flight Attendant, [undated] (Box 3)
    - Fun, [undated]; 2 (Box 3)
    - Golden State, [undated]; 3 (Box 3)
    - In The Grave You Can Turn The Other Cheek, [undated]; 2 (Box 3)
    - Gravity, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Happiness, [undated] (Box 3)
    - The History of Rose, 1983 (Box 3)
    - The Infection Scare, [undated] (Box 3)
    - International Gay Writings, [undated] (Box 3)
    - Italian Pleasures, 1996 (Box 3)
    - Italian Pleasures Reviews, 1996 (Box 3)
    - La Scala, 1997 (Box 3)
    - Leaving, [undated] (Box 3)
    - Letters From Aboard, [undated] (Box 3)
    - The Locket, [undated] (Box 3)
    - Losing Weight, [undated]; 2 (Box 4)
    - The Lost Language of Cranes, 1985-1989; 14 (Box 4)
    - Lost Language of the Cranes: reviews, 1991-1992; 2 (Box 4)
    - The Madonna of the Hens, [undated] (Box 5)
    - Malheur Country, [undated] (Box 5)
    - Il Medaglione, [undated] (Box 5)
    - In Memory of Another Emily, [undated] (Box 5)
    - Moment, [undated]; 2 (Box 5)
    - My Fathers Fish, [undated] (Box 5)
    - Old Folks, [undated] (Box 5)
    - Pacific Standard Time, [undated] (Box 5)
    - The Page Turner, 1997; 13 (Box 5)
    - The Page Turner: reviews, 1998 (Box 5)
    - Pages Passed From Hand to Hand, 1997; 5 (Box 6)
    - Pages Passed From Hand to Hand: reviews, 1998 (Box 6)
    - Paul Porterfield, [undated]; 3 (Box 6)
    - The Reindeer, [undated] (Box 6)
    - Sacred and Profane Love, [undated]; 2 (Box 6)
    - The Scruff, [undated] (Box 6)
    - The Season of Repeats, [undated] (Box 6)
    - Stories of Fathers, [undated] (Box 6)
    - Taking Care of Everything, [undated] (Box 6)
    - The Term Paper Artist, [undated] (Box 6)
    - Tobias Choate, [undated] (Box 6)
    - Two Florentine Portraits, [undated]; 2 (Box 6)
    - Two, [undated] (Box 6)
    - While England Sleeps, 1996-1997; 8 (Box 6)
    - While England Sleeps, 1996-1997; 15 (Box 7)
    - While England Sleeps Reviews, 1995 (Box 7)
    - White Horse Traveler, 1980; 2 (Box 7)
    - A Women, Her Daughter and Her Parakeet, [undated] (Box 7)
    - Yarn, [undated] (Box 7)
    - Poems, [undated]; 8 (Box 8)
    - Short stories, [undated]; 7 (Box 8)
    - Untitled manuscripts in notebooks, [undated]; 4 (Box 8)
    - Loose writings, high school, elementary, [undated]; 14 (Box 9)
    - Yale writings and work, 1980-1983; 2 (Box 10)
    - College essay, 1983 (Box 10)
    - Magazine short stories by Leavitt, 1982-1990; 7 (Box 10)
    - Magazine articles by Leavitt, 1988-1997; 8 (Box 10)
    - Articles by Leavitt, 1983-1995; 4 (Box 10)
    - Book covers, 1993-1997; 5 (Box 10)
    - Arkansas: notebook, undated (Box 11)
    - Arkansas: manuscript., 1997 (Box 11)
    - Arkansas: proofs, 1997; 2 (Box 11)
    - The Penguin Book of Gay Short Stories: proof, 1994; 2 (Box 11)
    - The Penguin Book of International Gay Writing: proofs, 1994-1995 (Box 12)
    - Little Brown & Company catalogue, 1998 (Box 12)
  - Articles on Leavitt
    - Magazine articles on Leavitt, 1983-1998; 21 (Box 13)
    - Articles on Leavitt, clippings, 1984-1998; 12 (Box 13)
  - Reviews
    - Novels, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Equal Affections, 1989 (Box 13)
    - A Place I've Never Been, 1990 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous reviews, 1993; 2 (Box 13)
    - Ads, 1993-1997 (Box 13)
    - Book cover jackets, [undated] (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, [undated] (Box 14)
  - Personal Papers
    - Scrapbooks, [undated]; 2 (Box 15)
    - Photographs, 1960-1997; 6 (Box 15)
    - High school diploma, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Yale acceptance letter, 1978 (Box 15)
    - Year books, 1975-1983; 6 (Box 15)
    - Personal papers, [undated]; 2 (Box 16)
    - Pamphlets, 1986-1994 (Box 16)
    - Calendar, 1997 (Box 16)
    - Writings, [undated]; 3 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1982-1986; 3 (Box 16)
    - Newspapers, 1986; 1992; 2 (Box 16)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1993-1997; 3 (Box 16)
    - Map, undated (Box 16)
    - Magazines, 1985-1992; 2 (Box 16)
    - Awards, 1979; undated; 2 (Box 16)
    - Stickers, Embroidered Cloth, Literary Quarterly (Box 17)
  - Audiovisual Material and Computer Disks
    Box 17 and 74 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Videocassette tapes
      - "Thirteen/WNET Great Performances #1719 'The Lost Language of Cranes' Preliminary Packaging - Not For Air", 1992 March 6; YCALMSS724_0004; 1; 01:28:04 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002102339299)
        A note written on the tape's box reads: David - Pls. return when finished. We will give you a copy once we have nicely packaged it. P.
        Restricted fragile material.
      - "Leavitt 'PI' 4/14/97", 1997 April 14; YCALMSS724_0005; 1; 00:22:15 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002102339307)
      - "Belgian Radio and Television 'Vie Schrijft die Blijft'", 1986 January 10; YCALMSS724_0006; 1; 00:51:51 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002102339315)
        Lieven Tavernier "Over Water;" Lieve Joris "De Golf;" David Leavitt "Family Dance"
      - "Dael Prichard", undated; YCALMSS724_0007; 1; 00:11:49 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002102339323)
      - "David Leavitt 4/11/89", 1989 April 11; YCALMSS724_0008; 1; 00:12:36 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002102339331)
      - "David Levitt for Sarah", 1989; YCALMSS724_0009; 1; 01:03:14 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002102339349)
    - Computer disks: 3.5" floppy, 52
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0001: "FB #18"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0002: unlabeled
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0003: "AAAA part 2"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0004: "Copy of System Folds"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0005: unlabeled
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0006: unlabeled
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0007: "BU #14"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0008: "FB #6"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0009: unlabeled
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0010: unlabeled
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0011: "FB #9"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0012: unlabeled
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0013: "FB Emergency Backup"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0014: "Backup #12"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0015: "FB #11"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0016: "BU #17"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0017: unlabeled
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0018: "Fastback Backup"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0019: "BU #20"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0020: "BU #5"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0021: "Fastback Backup #1"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0022: "BU Catalogue"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0023: unlabeled
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0024: "Backup #13"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0025: "Word [?] copy"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0026: "Another Word"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0027: "BU #23"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0028: "#25"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0029: "FB #3"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0030: "FB #4"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0031: "FB #7"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0032: "FB #8"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0033: "FB #10"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0034: "FB #15"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0035: "#19"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0036: unlabeled
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0037: "FB #21"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0038: "FB #2"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0039: "The Law of Falling"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0040: "FB #22"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0041: "More backup"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0042: "#28"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0043: "SCRABBLE"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0044: unlabeled
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0045: "BU #26"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0046: "BU #16"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0047: "MacIntosh Utilities #27"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0048: "MacIntosh Hypercard Idea"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0049: "MacIntosh Hypercard: stacks"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0050: "MacIntosh Hypercard Help"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0051: "Resume Creator"
      1998-ycal-0601-k-0052: "Suitcase"
      - FB #18, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0001; 1 (Box 18)
        Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0601-k-0002; 1 (Box 18)
      - AAAA part 2, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0003; 1 (Box 18)
      - Copy of system folder, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0004; 1 (Box 18)
      - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0601-k-0005; 1 (Box 18)
      - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0601-k-0006; 1 (Box 18)
      - BU #14, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0007; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB #6, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0008; 1 (Box 18)
      - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0601-k-0009; 1 (Box 18)
      - New Word, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0010; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB #9, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0011; 1 (Box 18)
      - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0601-k-0012; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB Emergency Backup, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0013; 1 (Box 18)
      - Back Up #12, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0014; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB #11, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0015; 1 (Box 18)
      - BU #17, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0016; 1 (Box 18)
      - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0601-k-0017; 1 (Box 18)
      - further backup, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0018; 1 (Box 18)
      - BU #20, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0019; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB #5, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0020; 1 (Box 18)
      - Fastback Backup #1, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0021; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB Catalogue, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0022; 1 (Box 18)
      - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0601-k-0023; 1 (Box 18)
      - Backup #13, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0024; 1 (Box 18)
      - WORD COPY COPY, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0025; 1 (Box 18)
      - Another word, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0026; 1 (Box 18)
      - 1. Microsoft Word L05 BU #23, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0027; 1 (Box 18)
      - #25, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0028; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB #3, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0029; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB #4, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0030; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB #7, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0031; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB #8, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0032; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB #10, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0033; 1 (Box 18)
      - BU #15, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0034; 1 (Box 18)
      - #19, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0035; 1 (Box 18)
      - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0601-k-0036; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB #21, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0037; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB #2, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0038; 1 (Box 18)
      - The Last of Falling Bodies Pro 1,2,3, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0039; 1 (Box 18)
      - FB #22 Copy of Novel, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0040; 1 (Box 18)
      - more backup, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0041; 1 (Box 18)
      - #28, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0042; 1 (Box 18)
      - SCRABBLE, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0043; 1 (Box 18)
      - [no label information], 1998-ycal-0601-k-0044; 1 (Box 18)
      - BU #26, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0045; 1 (Box 18)
      - BU #16, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0046; 1 (Box 18)
      - #27, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0047; 1 (Box 18)
      - Macintosh HyperCard Ideas, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0048; 1 (Box 18)
      - Macintosh HyperCard and Stacks, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0049; 1 (Box 18)
      - Macintosh HyperCard Help, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0050; 1 (Box 18)
      - Easy Working RESUME CREATOR FOR THE IBM, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0051; 1 (Box 18)
      - SUITCASE II, 1998-ycal-0601-k-0052; 1 (Box 18)
    - Audiocassette tapes
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - PEN/Faulkner Gala "Illusions", 1992 October 5; 1 (Box 59, Item barcode 39002099366107)
      - Speak Up, Interview with David Leavitt / "All Aboard: The Palace on Wheels", 1986 May 15; 1 (Box 59, Item barcode 39002099366115)
      - "Book Show #241, David Leavitt, 1997 November 7; 1 (Box 59, Item barcode 39002099366123)
  - Restricted Fragile
    - The Lost Language of Cranes, typescript corrected (Box 46)
      Restricted Fragile Material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
- March 2002 Acquisition, circa 2000; 2; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  Purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 2002.
  - Martin Bauman; or, A Sure Thing: typescript, two drafts; newspaper clippings (photocopies) and other related printed material, 12 (Box 19)
  - Martin Bauman; or, A Sure Thing: typescript, two drafts; newspaper clippings (photocopies) and other related printed material, 12 (Box 20)
- May 2006 Acquisition, 1981-2005; 3; 21.96; (24 boxes)
  Box 42 (audiovisual material): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 45 (computer disks): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Donald Windham-Sandy Campbell Collection Endowment Fund, 2006.
  Arranged under four headings: Correspondence, Writings and Related Papers, Audiovisual Material, and Other Papers.
  Contains correspondence, writings, printed material, audio cassettes, video cassettes, compact disk and one oil painting relating to the life and writing career of David Leavitt.
  - Correspondence
    - "A" (Box 21)
    - "B" (Box 21)
    - "C" (Box 21)
    - "D" (Box 21)
    - "E" (Box 21)
    - "F" (Box 21)
    - "G" (Box 21)
    - "H" (Box 21)
    - "I-J" (Box 21)
    - "K" (Box 21)
    - "L" (Box 21)
    - "M" (Box 21)
    - "N" (Box 21)
    - "O" (Box 21)
    - "P" (Box 21)
    - "Q-R" (Box 21)
    - "S" (Box 21)
    - "T" (Box 21)
    - "U-V" (Box 21)
    - "W-X" (Box 21)
    - "Y-Z" (Box 21)
    - Fan mail, 2 (Box 21)
  - Writings and related papers
    - Cover for "A Dog's Life" (Box 22)
    - [unidentified typescript] (Box 22)
    - "Marble Quilt;" " Wool Street" (Box 22)
    - "The Marble Quilt;" "The Good Faggot" (Box 22)
    - "The Documents Must Agree;" (Box 22)
    - "The Scruff of the Neck", 2 (Box 22)
    - Query for "American Nervousness," email correspondence (Box 22)
    - Query, 3 (Box 22)
    - "Crossing Border" (Box 22)
    - Publicity documents (Box 22)
    - "Martin Bauman, or a Sure Thing" (Box 22)
    - "Black Box," "We Meet at Last" (Box 22)
    - "Arkansas," translation (Box 22)
    - "La Nuova generazione perduta" (Box 22)
    - "The Scruff of the Neck" (Box 22)
    - "Crossing St. Gothard" (Box 22)
    - [unidentified typescript] (Box 22)
    - Web research on Lord Alfred Douglas and typescript (Box 22)
    - "The Infection Scene," typescript (Box 22)
    - Typescript on Douglas (Box 22)
    - "The Infection Scene", 3folders (Box 22)
    - [unidentified typescripts], 9 (Box 23)
    - [unidentified typescripts], 6 (Box 23)
    - "Flint's First Principle," typescript (Box 23)
    - "I'm Not Here," typescript (Box 23)
    - "Two Tents," etc. (Box 23)
    - "The Christmas Jew," etc. (Box 23)
    - "A Few Boys Forced to Your" (Box 23)
    - "Deviled Egg Plate," etc. (Box 23)
    - "At the Children's Table," etc. (Box 23)
    - "Dear Mr. Terrier," etc. (Box 23)
    - "The Age of Thespians" (Box 23)
    - "The Glass Bottom Boat," etc., 2 (Box 23)
    - "Heaped Earth," "Flint's First Principle" (Box 23)
    - "Sleeping Arrangements" (Box 23)
    - "Forced to Tour," etc. (Box 23)
    - "Because Very Few Mice Know How To Dance," etc. (Box 23)
    - "Ready to Pounce on a Sure Thing" (Box 23)
    - "Trial Marriage," etc. (Box 23)
    - "Arkansas", 1999 (Box 24)
    - Author's guild, 1999; 2 (Box 24)
    - Catalogs, 1998 (Box 24)
    - Catalog, 1999 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1999; 2 (Box 24)
    - Early books (Box 24)
    - Forster, 1999 (Box 24)
    - Magazine work, 1999 (Box 24)
    - Martin Bauman, 1999 (Box 24)
    - Non-fiction (Box 24)
    - "The Page Turner", 1998 (Box 24)
    - Photographs, 1998, undated (Box 24)
    - Photographs (Box 24)
    - Printed, 1998 (Box 24)
    - Tchaikovsky (Box 24)
    - Travel and Leisure article (Box 24)
    - "While England Sleeps", 1998 (Box 24)
    - Yale, 1998-1999 (Box 24)
    - "Martin Bauman; or, A Sure Thing," proofs, 2000; 11 (Box 24)
    - La nouva generazione perduta: proofs, 1998 (Box 24)
    - Notebook, undated (Box 24)
    - "Food and Wine," with Leavitt essay (Box 25)
    - "Gulliver," with Leavitt article, 1999 September (Box 25)
    - "Fun," "In the Piazza," "The Locket" (Box 25)
    - "Moment, Taking Care of Everything," notes (Box 25)
    - "Fun," "Infection Scene," etc. (Box 25)
    - "Infection Scene" (Box 25)
    - "The Infection Scene," typescript (Box 25)
    - "Scruff of the Neck," "Infection Scene" (Box 25)
    - "Infection Scene," "Scruff of the Neck", 2 (Box 25)
    - "Infection Scene," "Taking Care of Everything" (Box 25)
    - "Sacred and Profane Love," "Losing Weight" (Box 25)
    - "The Marble Quilt," "Crossing St. Gottard" (Box 25)
    - "Speonk," "The Marble Quilt," etc. (Box 25)
    - "Wool Street," etc., 2 (Box 25)
    - [unidentified typescript] (Box 25)
    - "Trattoria" (Box 25)
    - "Via in Selci" (Box 25)
    - "Marble Quilt," etc. (Box 25)
    - [unidentified typescripts], 6 (Box 25)
    - The Page Turner (Box 25)
    - Martin Bauman, typescripts, 4 (Box 26)
    - [unidentified typescript], 5 (Box 26)
    - [unidentified typescript], 6 (Box 26)
    - [unidentified typescripts], 14 (Box 27)
    - Chapter Seven: At the Children's Table (Box 28)
    - Stories II, 4 (Box 28)
    - Pages Passed From Hand to Hand, 3 (Box 28)
    - An Ear Worm (Box 28)
    - Pages Passed From Hand to Hand, 2 (Box 28)
    - The Page Turner (Box 28)
    - "Food of Love" (Box 29)
    - "In Maremma" uncorrected bound galley, 2 (Box 29)
    - The Perseus Books Group, catalog (Box 29)
    - "The Marble Quilt" [typescript], 2 (Box 29)